<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bianca Pereira</title>
    <description>Website</description>
    <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bianca-pereira.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:03:22 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:03:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>I love Google! And that is why I am leaving it..</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; have been using Google products since 2004. Now it is time to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love applications developed by Google. I started using them many years ago, starting by Google Search Engine and after became hooked by Gmail. All applications are easy to use, have my data always available whenever I need, and the best of all ‘it is free’. For who never had money to pay for anything technological, the ‘free’ aspect was always the decisive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today things have changed. I learned that ‘free’ does not really means free. I mean, I am ok with receiving advertisement in a non-ostensive way. And to be honest I am not sure if I really care for the fact that some government is looking up at my data, I just hope I will never regret that. But what I do care is about ‘having a choice’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone may say that we do have a choice when choosing products. That there is a free market where we can decide to go with X or Z. However, stopping to think a little bit I am not quite sure about that. It is hard to think that we will change Google for a small search engine, Amazon for a smaller retailer, or Facebook for another (which one?) social network. Together with Apple and Microsoft, these companies are currently known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/21/technology/techs-frightful-5-will-dominate-digital-life-for-foreseeable-future.html&quot;&gt;‘The Frightful 5’&lt;/a&gt;. The reason for this name seems to be the fact that, there is no way to get away from them. Our lives are already based on their products, without real chances to move away, and any real competition not only does not affect them but fortifies them. As soon as a competitor grows, it gets acquired; which means, the more competition the less competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I decided to do an &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/how-is-life-without-facebook-and-twitter/&quot;&gt;experiment of one week without Facebook and Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It was interesting but not that hard since I do not use that much social media. But Google!? Knowledge is my life. Would I be able to have a functional life without having Google at all!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘At all’ seems to much for me, but I decided to see which applications I can try experimenting living without. First, let’s see which applications I currently use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Bookmarks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GMail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Docs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Slides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Drive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Keep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Play&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Maps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Youtube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Translate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Photos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 applications!?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all those the most interesting part is.. I have no clue where my Bookmarks are stored because actually there is no real “Google Bookmarks”. Even so, my bookmarks and browsing history are “magically” sync with my Google account. So, talking about choice, I think we have a clear winner. I have never thought about where my bookmarks go, who sees them, what is done with them. In particular my browsing history. Sure, I DO want to know my browsing history and maybe even get some analytics from it. But no, I don’t want a company tapping this info for I don’t know what. I never really chose it, I just used it! Time for a change..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will start this experiment focusing on Google Bookmarks, but I will also add Google Chrome in the cutting out list just because I have no idea of what else gets linked with Google. Let’s see what Firefox has to offer. Also, time to take some decisions and choose another application to manage my bookmarks. But how to find one? Let me “Google It”… ops&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; have been using Google products since 2004. Now it is time to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/i-love-google-and-that-is-why-i-am-leaving-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/i-love-google-and-that-is-why-i-am-leaving-it/</guid>
        
        <category>google</category>
        
        <category>experiment</category>
        
        
        <category>Social</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Outlier, a loner or a leader?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;n the &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/the-herd-behaviour-and-the-comfort-zone/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I talked about the herd behaviour and how humans tend to follow the crowd. But, from time to time we see people coming from &quot;nowhere&quot; and becoming well succeeded on something. Those are &lt;i&gt;the outliers&lt;/i&gt;, but how do they arrive there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the name outlier comes from a point out of a distribution. It is something or someone different from the average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://i0.wp.com/flowingdata.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/outlier.gif&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://i0.wp.com/flowingdata.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/outlier.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Outlier in mathematics&quot; /&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The outlier&lt;/figcaption&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last post we explained that an individual can have two positions in a herd: the center, or the border. The main difference of those is that the individuals in the center are safer but do not have room to move; they just follow wherever the herd goes. In opposition, those individuals at the border are more suscetible to the danger from the environment, but have almost complete freedom of movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The individuals in the center are the majority; they are &lt;em&gt;the average&lt;/em&gt;. Those individuals in the border are minority; let’s call them &lt;em&gt;the frontier&lt;/em&gt;. An outlier is one of the individuals in the frontier that goes out of the limit of the heard, and farther from the average. In other words, it is the one who wants to stop following the herd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an individual starts becoming an outlier, it can become one of two types: a solitary, or a leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###The Solitary Outlier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solitary outlier is the one who leaves alone. It leaves without anyone and walk alone his own path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A herd exists for protection of its members. Alone, individuals are more likely to face a danger and perish. When an outlier goes out of the herd and decides to stay alone, it is likely it will die or be forced to go back to the safety of the herd. As social animals, humans are very likely to perish if completely alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting (real) story of a solitary outlier is represented in the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0758758/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/a&gt;. There, a guy decides to survive alone in Alaska alone. At the end of the movie… well better you watch to discover =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/into-the-wild.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/into-the-wild.jpg&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Into the Wild&quot; /&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/figcaption&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###The Leader Outlier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leader outlier is the one capable to go out but without being alone. It leads part (or maybe the whole) heard with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another type of outlier takes advantage of one of the simple rules from the herd: the alignment (for all rules check my &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/the-herd-behaviour-and-the-comfort-zone/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;). This rule says that one should move in alignment with those in its field of vision. As soon as the outlier starts to go out of the border and farther from the average, those near it start to follow and go out of the herd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is important to notice that without the first followers, the leader would not be succesful and would become a solitary outlier. The following video demonstrates my point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fW8amMCVAJQ?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, would you prefer live in your comfort zone or take an outlier adventure? And what do you prefer, a solitary or a leader outlier?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;n the &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/the-herd-behaviour-and-the-comfort-zone/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I talked about the herd behaviour and how humans tend to follow the crowd. But, from time to time we see people coming from &quot;nowhere&quot; and becoming well succeeded on something. Those are &lt;i&gt;the outliers&lt;/i&gt;, but how do they arrive there?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/outlier-a-loner-or-a-leader/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/outlier-a-loner-or-a-leader/</guid>
        
        <category>herd</category>
        
        <category>complexity</category>
        
        <category>outlier</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Herd Behaviour and the Comfort Zone</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;ollowing my &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/how-is-life-without-facebook-and-twitter/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I read an interesting view from Onishiroi on how, even after more than thousand years, humans keep following the allegory of the cave from Plato. (For more details check &lt;a href=&quot;http://onishiroi.blogspot.com/2015/10/a-evolucao-da-caverna.html&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt; in Brazilian Portuguese). This makes me think on what is called the &lt;b&gt;Herd Behaviour&lt;/b&gt; and this is the theme of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody learned in the school at some point about packs, flocks, fish schools and so on. These are social groupings of animals, e.g. buffalos, birds, and fishes. What few people know is that humans follow the same behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prank played by a Brazilian television channel exemplifies what I am talking about. In the prank a crowd arrives and someone shouts &lt;em&gt;“Take care with the shooting”&lt;/em&gt; and in the sequence (after no shooting) someone shout &lt;em&gt;“RUN!”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TUdVvelMCKI?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is a crowd presenting a given behavior, the most basic reaction is to follow the crowd “just in case”. In this moment, before having the real view of what is going on, the natural reaction is go with the crowd, a “herd behavior”. The goal of the herd arrangement is to provide security for each individual by creating a body that is stronger than its parts. Another example is the experiment of the elevator, where everyone enter in the elevator but rather than face the door, they face the wall. What would be the behaviour of those entering in the elevator?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1GSzCBv1-qA?list=PLQy4q7r6flY5Ex5HvptZ_kAcUMkUzoyCp&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When studying the movements of birds, researchers discovered that herd behaviour could be simulated by three simples rules: separation, alignment, and cohesion. Separation is the rule that says a bird should avoid bumping into another bird while flying. If you stop to think, this is the same when you are in a crowd. If you just stop while the crowd is running, it is likely they will hurt you and you hurt someone else. The second rule, alignment, says you should move as those in your field of vision are moving. As in the prank, if everyone is going in one direction then probably that is the safest direction to go. The third and last simple rule is the cohesion that says you should be as closer as possible to those around you. Basically, those closest to you are the ones most able to provide you security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The herd behaviour is a way to keep us safe when alone we may not make it. But as it provides comfort it also has some side effects: the creation of the famous “comfort zone”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/herd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/herd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sheeps in a herd&quot; /&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A flock of sheep&lt;/figcaption&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the picture above. Who is more protected? The one in the middle or the one in the border? If a predator comes to attack, those in the middle are the safest ones. They do not need to be so scared as soon as they keep themselves in the middle. But the side effect is, they can only go where the herd goes. They have no choice where to go because according to the three rules, they should not bump in anyone, follow who is around, and stay close to their peers. As it may sounds interesting for survival purposes, we are humans and we do like to have choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comfort zone is that place in the very middle of the herd. There is no choice where to go, if one like it or not, but there is a good feeling of safety. Whatever is out there will not arrive at you and this has everything to do with the allegory of the cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever is out there (the shadows) will not catch you, as soon as you keep as you are. Stay in the safety. If the ones in the border want to leave the herd, don’t allow them to do that, it is unsafe for them out there and even more for you. As thinner the distance between you and the border as less safe it will be for you. Because soon or later, as the border disperse you will become the border, and this is not a good place to be. That is the comfort zone and this is the social pressure to keep anyone from leave the crowd and to stay exactly where they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the simplicity of this model and I do believe we move in life as in herd, but there are two remaining questions. Who guides the herd when they change directions (as in the video below)? And, what is the role of the ones in the border (i.e. the outliers)? These are questions for another post ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XH-groCeKbE?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;ollowing my &lt;a href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/blog/how-is-life-without-facebook-and-twitter/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I read an interesting view from Onishiroi on how, even after more than thousand years, humans keep following the allegory of the cave from Plato. (For more details check &lt;a href=&quot;http://onishiroi.blogspot.com/2015/10/a-evolucao-da-caverna.html&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt; in Brazilian Portuguese). This makes me think on what is called the &lt;b&gt;Herd Behaviour&lt;/b&gt; and this is the theme of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-herd-behaviour-and-the-comfort-zone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-herd-behaviour-and-the-comfort-zone/</guid>
        
        <category>herd</category>
        
        <category>complexity</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How is Life Without Facebook and Twitter?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;One&lt;/span&gt; week ago I decided to take a break from Facebook and Twitter. I am tired of not having time. I arrive at home from work, open Facebook for few minutes and suddenly 3 hours had passed. What did happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call it the &lt;strong&gt;timeline vortex&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a moment where what appears in the timeline is so interesting that we go from post to post, changing from one website and video to another. And the timeline is infinite, as much you scroll down as much you get new information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, during the full moon eclipse I noticed that, even when the moon was red and huge in the sky, every one walked at the street without noticing it. It made me think on how many distractions we have that do not allow us to see the obvious, to see what is in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to do an experiment: One week without access Facebook or Twitter. And here is the result on what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first hours after my decision were already hard. As soon as I want to relax from study and work I automatically move my mouse to the Twitter app icon. Every time a thought pop up in my mind I think on how I could explain that in a Facebook post. I thought it would pass after few days, but the problems changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second day I had the problem of finding an information I already had. I was looking for a project I did not remember the name but I knew it was on Twitter. But well, no Twitter, remember? I went to Google like crazy looking for one keyword after another and nothing. And to complete my agony, the top results from my search were always Facebook pages. Finally, after around 6 different queries I found what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third difficulty happened on mornings. I acquired the habit of taking the first minutes in the day to read news, and my source of news is.. Twitter. That was hard to beat. I usually do not have interest in formal media then I just decided to not read anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth problem is, which sounds quite like cheating my experiment, Twitter notifications on the cell phone and Facebook emails. Although I was not connecting to Facebook and been trapped in the timeline vortex I could still receive the contact from my friends. But, I could not answer. Also, once I clicked on the Twitter notification by instinct just before shout “noooo. I do not want to read that!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, despite of learning that these social medias are a part of my life hard to change, I also got some good lessons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Without the timeline I could look for information I want, instead of receive information passively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had much more time to read books (I finished a full book).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook does not make me more social despite I like and share pieces of information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook is a good way to share my thoughts and discuss, until I get trapped in the Timeline vortex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twitter is a good way to share information (without discuss it). For some reason I feel less the timeline vortex in Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Without Facebook and Twitter I procrastinate less.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of this week were positive, but the question that remains is: &lt;strong&gt;How to know more about my friends and interesting things they share without been trapped in the timeline vortex?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this experiment I think I can use social media more mindful and avoid the timeline vortex. The next week will be to discover if I really learned that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/facebook-stats.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/facebook-stats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook Stats&quot; /&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Status after one week without Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;One&lt;/span&gt; week ago I decided to take a break from Facebook and Twitter. I am tired of not having time. I arrive at home from work, open Facebook for few minutes and suddenly 3 hours had passed. What did happen?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/how-is-life-without-facebook-and-twitter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/how-is-life-without-facebook-and-twitter/</guid>
        
        <category>facebook</category>
        
        <category>twitter</category>
        
        <category>social media</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Full Moon Eclipse</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt; happens the super moon total eclipse. I knew the full eclipse would be at 8pm at my location and I knew the moon would be in the east. I looked through my window and nothing, no moon. I then decided to go out of home looking for a place with less trees and buildings where I could see it. I walked around and suddenly stopped in the middle of the footpath. It was there, it was happening and I could see it. In the entrance of a condominium between two buildings. I stopped and spent 20 minutes there until the full eclipse and a bit after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile many people passed. Cars, people jogging, people walking listening music on their phones. A considerable amount of people. They passed, a person stopped in the middle of the footpath, they passed. I was there facing a super moon eclipse happening just in front of me. They passed, nobody saw it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt; happens the super moon total eclipse. I knew the full eclipse would be at 8pm at my location and I knew the moon would be in the east. I looked through my window and nothing, no moon. I then decided to go out of home looking for a place with less trees and buildings where I could see it. I walked around and suddenly stopped in the middle of the footpath. It was there, it was happening and I could see it. In the entrance of a condominium between two buildings. I stopped and spent 20 minutes there until the full eclipse and a bit after.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-full-moon-eclipse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-full-moon-eclipse/</guid>
        
        <category>eclipse</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Avatar Path</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Who&lt;/span&gt; does not remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0417299/?ref_=fn_al_tt_5&quot;&gt;Aang, the Last Airbender&lt;/a&gt;? The child monk who have to learn how to deal with the four elements to help saving the world even when he is just a child. This cartoon was an Eureka moment in my life, I watched it and I finally discovered: &quot;I know what I want to be. I want to be an Avatar.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/aang.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/aang.jpg&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Aang&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aang, the Last Airbender&lt;/figcaption&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avatar is a person who manifests in the world something bigger than itself, the Avatar is an instrument. The cartoon presents the idea in a nice way by showing how much hardwork it requires to become and be an Avatar and how much self-improvement Aang needs to work on to make it happen. Self-improvement and manifestation, this is the Avatar Path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part of the Avatar mission is not the goal of a perfect manifestation but the path itself. The Avatar works on its improvement and can also act as a tutor to others (in a Master-Disciple manner). In each step in order to become an Avatar, the ability to manifest grows, the “Avatar state” starts to appear and become more frequent and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real life, who are the Avatars? Entrepreneurs, teachers, doctors, philosophers… Avatars are leaders. Spiritual leaders, business leaders, all sort of leaders. In summary, all those who have a vision, improve themselves to manifest their vision, and bring others with them along the way (in a Master-Disciple manner).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Self-improvement and manifestation, this is the Avatar Path.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, do not confuse it with job roles. Just because someone is a priest, a CEO, a PhD, or whatever title you may want to give, it does not make it a leader. Leaders are those in the path to enter in the Avatar state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how to become an Avatar? Well, I still do not know but I have some idea. There are three main points that I envision for who wants to become an Avatar. The first one is self-improvement, the second is manifestation, and the third one is tutoring. In this post I will cover the first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-improvement happens through the development of skills. Have a diploma does not prove someone has a skill and it also does not prove someone have all skills needed to become an Avatar. In order to become an Avatar, one needs to develop the skills needed for manifestation. To explain what I mean by that I will use a system of “mystic” studies, stay with me a little bit and you will see there is nothing so mystic after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I enrolled in a 8 weeks course about chakras with &lt;a href=&quot;https://holisticmummy.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Dolores Garvin&lt;/a&gt;. For who studies “mysticism” they are explained as energetic centers of the body. But what I found most interesting is how they can be used to explain the path for liberation and manifestation. The liberation of the self happens when a person can express itself to the world without fears and barriers. The manifestation happens when someone can observe and capture abstract ideas from the world and manifest it in the reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system of chakras contains seven main chakras located along the spine. The energetic flow from the first to the seventh chakra promotes liberation, while the opposite flow, from seventh to first, promotes manifestation. One flow does not happen without the other, and only opening the chakras (keeping them in balance) makes the energy flows. I cannot talk about energy here since I know almost nothing about it, but what I want to say is how the chakras perfectly map into skills that anyone can develop, and how it can bring someone to manifest its visions and become an Avatar. As our focus is on manifestation I will start to explain from the seventh chakra. I would like to reinforce it is still a “work in progress” (and will always be =p) then do not try to kill me if I change my mind completely in, I don’t know, 5 minutes =p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/chakras.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chakras.png&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Location of the chakras&quot; /&gt; 
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The location of the chakras&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;seventh chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is located at the top of the head. This chakra is associated with the Universe, that some people like to call God. I like to call it the network. Who never heard about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butterfly_effect&quot;&gt;Butterfly effect&lt;/a&gt;? All of us are part of a network, when someone does something, all others get affected. Therefore there is nothing so insignificant that cannot make an impact on the whole network, and there is no one so important that can move the whole network. The skill associated with this chakra is to understand itself as part of this network, and understand there are two forces been applied. The force of action, where you can move the net, and the reactive force where the net moves and you need to accept. The network is alive and the Avatar is just part of it. Have a very good seventh chakra is be aware of it and learn how to deal with this “invisible” network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sixth chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is just under the seventh one. It is called the third eye and is located at the middle of the forefront. The third eye represents the vision, our capacity to perceive the reality as is, without illusions or preconceptions. One of the skills that can be related to the third eye is the creativity, the most intellectual one. In this case, creativity is the capacity to see the world through different perspectives, in special in the ways no one saw before. For creativity I highly recommend the course of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.murilogun.com.br/palestra/criatividade-2&quot;&gt;Murilo Gun&lt;/a&gt;, although I do not know if he has content available in English. Another skill (if we can see as that) related to the third eye is the development of a healthy mindset, a way of thinking, a way on how to see the world. As a pointer for this I recommend the book: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mindsetonline.com/whatisit/about/&quot;&gt;Mindset, the new psychology of success&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going down to the next chakra. The &lt;strong&gt;fifth chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is located at the throat and it is related to communication. Communication is not only speak, and speak well, but also knows how to listen, be present, give attention to the speaker, understand its feelings and emotions more than the words themselves. There is no effective communication if both parts cannot understand each other. The communication can happens through many ways such as by speaking but also by writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fourth chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is the one that makes the bridge between the external and the internal. This chakra is located at the level of the heart and its skill is empathy. One who wants to manifest something into the world needs to be emphatic, needs to understand how people think and feel. Remember that the Avatar eventually becomes a leader, not a boss. A leader because it helps others to grow, a boss imposes how they should grow. To help someone, first it is needed to understand the person, to lately understand what help really means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;third chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is part of the personal sphere. It is located at the solar plexus and it is related to personal power. By personal power I mean the capacity of the person to be itself, have self-confidence and self-motivation. Very often we seek external validation and we end up measuring our steps by what others will talk about us and if they will approve us. This chakra is about be OK with yourself, decide your path, go for it and take responsibility for it. If I can map it into skills they would be initiative, independence, confidence, and self-motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;second chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is near the sexual region, just below the belly button. This chakra is also related to creativity but a more visceral one. The creativity that comes from the movement, from the body itself. Remember that in this region is the place where happens the “creation of life”. The best relation I can currently do is the association with African music and dance. One does not rationalize the drums, one feels the drums. And it makes you move, almost instinctively. Often we need to make effort to not move (or we made this effort already by blocking any movement we could possibly have =/). The skill for this chakra is also the creativity, but the personal one, the capacity of express feelings and thoughts through motion or something physical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;first chakra&lt;/strong&gt; is the last one for the manifestation to happen. And to be honest, I could never fully understand this chakra, sorry =p This chakra represents the most visceral part of humans, it represents the survival instincts. When dying by starvation one does not think “I will eat a nice red apple that I will catch in this and that way”, one goes, grab the apple and eat it. That’s it! The first chakra means “Do it”, it represents the capacity of delivery, the capacity to take the elements of the world and translate the abstract through those elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to become an Avatar is self-improvement, is to develop skills but not just one, all those needed to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eRukzTMSTnc&quot;&gt;open the path&lt;/a&gt;”. In this process, the vision the person wants to follow becomes more and more clear and the capacity to manifest grows. As much the Avatar evolves in this path, as clearer the vision and stronger the manifestation. One that do not follow the path, cannot arrive at the final goal. The path is the goal. Happy Avatar path for you =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, I will really appreciate if you share your opinion with me at the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Who&lt;/span&gt; does not remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0417299/?ref_=fn_al_tt_5&quot;&gt;Aang, the Last Airbender&lt;/a&gt;? The child monk who have to learn how to deal with the four elements to help saving the world even when he is just a child. This cartoon was an Eureka moment in my life, I watched it and I finally discovered: &quot;I know what I want to be. I want to be an Avatar.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-avatar-path/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/the-avatar-path/</guid>
        
        <category>mindset</category>
        
        <category>avatar</category>
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
        <category>self-confidence</category>
        
        <category>manifestation</category>
        
        <category>chakra</category>
        
        
        <category>Skills</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>There is no problem in rediscovering the wheel</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;There&lt;/span&gt; is no problem in rediscovering the wheel if you have never discovered it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The school system was created to prepare the students to learn how to remember the “correct” solution for a problem given. There is no stimulus to observe and delimit new problems or come up with a new solution, in special if it is less eficcient than the one given by the teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/school.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/school.jpg&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;School class&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When some of those students arrive at a research graduate level, the goal subtly changes. Now, the student needs to create something new: identify a new problem, or develop q better solution for a problem already solved. Students arrive with that in mind and may think: “But how do I start?”. There was no previous preparation for such journey but still, if you enter in the degree program it means you are prepared, aren’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment the student enter in a Research Degree may have a big influence in the student’s mindset. Carol S. Dweck explains in the Book “&lt;a href=&quot;http://mindsetonline.com/whatisit/about/&quot;&gt;Mindset, the new psychology of success&lt;/a&gt;” that there are two types of mindset: the fixed mindset, and the growth mindset. The fixed mindset is when a person feels ready for the challenges, as if there is no more to learn and only to apply the inate skills. In opposition, in the growth mindset the person is always trying to learn and improve all its skills, all the time. If someone from the fixed mindset fail, the person feels as a failure. The person who has already all skills required cannot fail, right? Otherwise it does not have the skills and is not suitable for the challenge. In the growth mindset, in case of fail, the person sees the failure as an opportunity to learn and to improve itself. If something goes wrong is because it was not ready yet, but it will learn and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone pass through the hard challenge to enter in an undergraduate course, the mindset may got affected. You are the best over all students who tried! You have the skills! You are! This can easily put someone on the fixed mindset, but the first exams put all this idea into challenge very soon. You were bad in the exam, or you learn or you are out. What will it be? This can be a good moment to put the student again in a growth mindset if posed in a good way, because at the end of the day you are a student, aren’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things happen a little differently in a reserach program, such as a PhD. You enter, you passed, you are good, now you will create something new never seen before. And here we go for the fixed mindset again. But now without easy return. There are no tests, there are (supposedly) no steps to follow, until the moment comes. Where are the papers you cannot create? Where is the thesis you cannot write? Where is the presentation you cannot organize? And the answer may be: wait, I could not find any new problem or idea for a revolution, I need more time. More time, more stress, less time, less motivation. And it happens so fast that when one realizes it has passed two, three, four years and things just got worse and worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/person-time.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/person-time.jpg&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Person pointing to a watch&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this pressure on novelty and good results, a student may often forget the most important thing. The goal of any student is to learn, regardless of the degree. In the pressure for novelty, students do not try to “rediscover the wheel”, because the wheel is too old, it is not novelty. But the information that one always forget is that the wheel may have been discovered a long time ago, but if you do not know how it works then how to improve it? How to foreseen the unsolved problems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution? No one enter in a PhD because is ready to write a thesis, otherwise one would start the PhD by writing the Thesis. One stars a PhD to learn how to write a thesis, often with no indication on how to go for it. Thus the first step would be mindset change. Pose yourself in the growth mindset, see yourself as a student, and do reinvent the wheel. Go for the basics of your topic and build the ideas and the tools yourself from scratch, start by studying one, and only one, state-of-the-art solution. Understand it deeply, rebuild it, verify what is missing, and goes from that. Every house needs a foundation. Everyday ask yourself: What did I learn today that I did not know yesterday? It may still not give you a thesis, but it may be the first step to arrive there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/caveman-wheel.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/caveman-wheel.png&quot; height=&quot;50%&quot; alt=&quot;Caveman creating a wheel&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to know what you think about that. Please leave you opinion at the commens below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*All pictures in this article are from Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;There&lt;/span&gt; is no problem in rediscovering the wheel if you have never discovered it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/there-is-no-problem-in-rediscovering-the-wheel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/there-is-no-problem-in-rediscovering-the-wheel/</guid>
        
        <category>mindset</category>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
        
        <category>Skills</category>
        
        <category>PhD</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Where does the basketball hoop come from?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; believe our goal in life should be to be better everyday. And how to do it? Improving our skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless if it is for a job or just for fun I believe in evolution. And if you are evolving you need to change, for good or bad. Following that, I recently started an on-line course about Unblocking Creativity. I always imagined that I was not creative at all (maybe because I don’t really draw?) but there is already one year that I discovered me creative. But as much as I try to be creative and my mind flies I also feel there are blocking thoughts and habits that I need to get rid off. But, how to remove what you don’t know you have!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course I am following, in Portuguese, there was an interesting challenge to foster curiosity. The challenge was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;Observe something around you, an object or a solution, and try to figure out what were the ideas that were used to create it.&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the iPhone did not appear from nowhere, the palm top already had touch screen and the cell phones were already well known. Be creative is to get things that already exist, work on them, and transform them in something new. Pretty much what a researcher does =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the challenge I thought on where the basketball hoop comes from. The solution that, of course, came from my mind and there is no compromise with the reality, is the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;link rel=&quot;img_src&quot; href=&quot;http://biancapereira.me/assets/img/basketball-hoop.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/basketball-hoop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basketball Hoop&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intuition is simple: &lt;strong&gt;rubish bin + ball = basketball hoop&lt;/strong&gt;. It sounds pretty obvious when you try to throw that ball paper in the bin, but stop and think: is it true? Imagine a big basketballl court and one small bin at each side. How is someone supposed to see the bin in order to throw a ball inside?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, &lt;strong&gt;iteration number 1: rubish bin + high place + ball = basketball hoop&lt;/strong&gt;. Keep it simple, put the bin in a high place and now everyone can see. Perfect, extraordinary! But who will take the ball when someone throw it inside? It remembers me when I was a child and everybody hated to take the ball when it started to roll out at the street (given it was around 30 degrees of inclination). Ok, let’s make it easier then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration number 2: rubish bin - bottom + high place + ball = basketball hoop&lt;/strong&gt;. As there is no interest to take the ball inside of the bin all the time, let’s remove the bottom of the bin that the ball can just drop from there. Now, try it! I would guess that the ball will not pass quite easily through the tub formed by the bin and will get stuck anyway. In other words, our solution didn’t work quite as expected. Let’s try a new iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration number 3: rubish bin - bottom - 80% of the sides + high place + ball = basketball hoop&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s cut the sides and leave it smaller that the ball will not get stuck so easy. At then end what we will have is just a ring from what was previously a bin and now the ball can pass much easier. Let’s play!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- Point!&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- No!&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- Yes, it was point, didn&#39;t you see?&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- What are you talking about? It was out.&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- Of course it was in!&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;- Well, I think we have a problem here.&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is easier and faster for the ball to pass through the ring as much as it is to just bump on it without pass. Even though the previous problem is solved it is now hard to figure out if it was a point or not. We need to make the ball spend some time inside the “bin” and then go out alone. Wow! It looks super hi-tech! Can we really do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iteration number 4: rubish bin - bottom - 80% of the sides + soccer net + high place + ball = basketball hoop. A soccer net seems very handy for our problem. If included in a funnel shape the net can slow down the ball so that there is enough time to check if the ball entered in the hoop or not. And now it is fine, let’s gonna play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altough creativity just requires us to see possible combinations between things in the world, it is also necessary a lot of work to figure out how to make our combination works to solve a real problem. When it does happen then we have innovation, something the marketplace praises so much these days. Be more inovative, improve your skills, specially the creativity. Leave the boring job for robots and let’s be more humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If after my story you were curious about the real story of the basketball hoop here it is: [http://basketball.epicsports.com/basketball-hoop-history.html] (http://basketball.epicsports.com/basketball-hoop-history.html).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creativity course I am following is this one &lt;a href=&quot;http://reaprendizagemcriativa.com.br/&quot;&gt;http://reaprendizagemcriativa.com.br/&lt;/a&gt; (In Brazilian Portuguese).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon and leave your comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; believe our goal in life should be to be better everyday. And how to do it? Improving our skills.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/where-does-the-basketball-hoop-come-from/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/where-does-the-basketball-hoop-come-from/</guid>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
        
        <category>Skills</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Identity Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; am who I am, but can I prove it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I decided to start the gym. I chose the option closest to home and decided to get a free pass to see how it is, before decide for a full membership. Here I go with pass on hand (on cell phone actually), my gym clothes and lots of energy! Arriving there.. “Hi. Can I have your id?” Well, the pass says to bring the pass printed or on the cell phone, there is nothing about id there, but ok. I can come back later, maybe. Well, there is an option. To get the pass I need the ID but if I want to start today I can get the membership and that’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, wait… to get for free I need to identify myself but to get the FULL membership it is ok..?? That’s weird and this occasion made me remember a not so old discussion I would like to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently there was a huge discussion on social networks about the website &lt;a href=&quot;http://tudosobretodos.se/&quot;&gt;Tudo Sobre Todos&lt;/a&gt;. This website allows the collection of data from Brazilians such as: gender, full name, date of birth, full address, CPF (the registration number used for tax payment and many other public and bank services), parents and relatives, companies and societies the person participates, alternative addresses, and neighbours. Yes, all this for a good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brazilians went crazy!! Destroy this website! They are selling my informations!! Ai, ai… the website works fully on open data. Yes, open data! I decided to do a test. I looked for a random person on Facebook (one of those complaining) and I got almost all information. I got even number of the apartment, and everything just searching on Google, Facebook, and LinkedIn. People include information about who are their relatives as well as gender, name, and birthdate on their Facebook profile; the data about companies and societies is on LinkedIn; the CPF can be found online if the person did any public exam for University or public employment; and the address may be found if the person had anything related to a dispute of house or they have the house registered in their names. Everything public, everything there. It is only needed to look for it and start to match the informations, do some disambiguation and that’s it. With lots of data, the neighbours is something quite easy to get. And in this sense I clap for the website, they did it and it is not illegal, because the data is public. They just created the Database and still get the rights for the data because of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is interesting on that is.. how can I prove I am myself if everyone else can have all my data!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the very old times I would need to say I am daughter of someone, grandaughter of someone else, leaving in East/West/North/South of somewhere, and then maybe, someone will believe in me and/or recognize me. Later, important people had their rings to show their identity while others, who cares about who they are. Centuries later we started to have birth certificate, usually given by the church, and another certificate given to the family when the person died. Then we started to sign documents, and suddenly there were a sort of numbers that, in combination with more information, could prove that we were ourselves. All those methods of identification were based more or less in the idea that only the person has a given set of information (ring, specific number, etc). But and now that everybody can have all information about someone? How to prove identity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the era of Open Data what can we use as proof that we are who we are? From the example of the gym, I think the money may work as identification once again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; am who I am, but can I prove it?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/identity-crisis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/identity-crisis/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Identity Resolution</category>
        
        <category>Identity Uncertainty</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A short introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;magine, just for a second, a dreamer. From those kind of dreamers that see figures on the clouds, from those who envision the next technology, from those who believe in revolutions. Now, imagine a person under the curse of perfectionism. That person who wants to improve everything, that see each minor detail as a possible risk with 0.000001% of chance to happen, that is able to criticize and review each and any small part of an idea. Very different people, no? Now, merge both in a single person... That&#39;s hard, isn&#39;t it? Well, I am Bianca. Nice to meet you =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog was created with the intention of being what I like to call a “mind dump”. As my mind can dream more than my hands can work, it is always good to share ideas and knowledge that we acquire in this long journey called life. Here I am not planning to create a technical, personal, or any kind of blog to advertise one of my personas. The unique purpose is to share experiences and exchange opinions. I want to create a dump of my mind that can be readen and discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As promised in the title this is just a short introduction of what this website is supposed to be. See you in the next post!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;magine, just for a second, a dreamer. From those kind of dreamers that see figures on the clouds, from those who envision the next technology, from those who believe in revolutions. Now, imagine a person under the curse of perfectionism. That person who wants to improve everything, that see each minor detail as a possible risk with 0.000001% of chance to happen, that is able to criticize and review each and any small part of an idea. Very different people, no? Now, merge both in a single person... That&#39;s hard, isn&#39;t it? Well, I am Bianca. Nice to meet you =)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/a-short-introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bianca-pereira.github.io//blog/a-short-introduction/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Me</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
